A Guide to the Papers of the Jefferson National Bank ca. 1914-1998
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Advertising Material 1967-1997, n.d. (Carton 7-8 Also OS Boxes 1-12)
  - Private Banking (NB) n.d., Advertising boards (5 copies) (Oversize 11)
  - Statement of Condition (JNB) 1987 Sep 30, Advertising boards (Oversize 11)
  - 24-Hour Teller Card Request (NB) n.d., Advertising boards (Oversize 11)
  - When My Marina Was About To Go Under, Jefferson National Kept Me Afloat (JNB) n.d., Advertising boards (Oversize 11)
  - When Your Ship Comes In--For Financial Peace of Mind (JNB) n.d., Advertising boards (Oversize 11)
  - Annual Report Advertisements (NB) 1971, Advertising boards (Oversize 12)
  - The Financial Picture For Your Retirement May Not Be Clear--Our Advice On Retirement Plans Is (NB) n.d., Advertising boards (Oversize 12)
  - Interest Checking Is A Checking Account & A Savings Account (NB & Southern Bank) n.d., Advertising boards (Oversize 12)
  - Join a Christmas Savings Club at National Bank Today (NB) n.d., Advertising boards (Oversize 12)
  - A Money Market Account That's Everything A Money Market Account Should Be--INSURED (JNB) n.d., Advertising boards (Oversize 12)
  - Now! National Bank's Lovingston Office Is Open On Saturday. We Make Our Banking Fit Your Life (NB) n.d., Advertising boards (Oversize 12)
  - Putting Everything In Joint Names Solves All Your Estate Planning Problems. Right?... Wrong! (NB) n.d., Advertising boards (Oversize 12)
  - Statement of Condition (JNB) 1985 Mar 31, Advertising boards (2 pieces) (Oversize 12)
  - United States Road Atlas & Travel Guide (NB) n.d., Advertising boards (Oversize 12)
  - We'll Bet You A Gallon of Gas Our Bank Is Closer Than Your Bank (NB) n.d., Advertising boards (Oversize 12)
  - Why Our Interest Checking Is Bound To Be The Best In 25 Words Or Less (NB & Bank of Goochland) n.d., Advertising boards (2 copies) (Oversize 12)
  - You're Invited To See & Use Our Brand New Facilities At Two of Our Charlottesville Offices (NBTC) n.y. Jun 22-23, Advertising boards (Oversize 12)
  - Agreement & Disclosure--Jefferson Line 1987 Mar 6, Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - Are You A Gambler? Or Do You Like A Sure Thing? (NBTC) n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - The Bank That Is Close To You Is Now Closer To You (NBTC) n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - Banking At Your Fingertips (Southern Bank) n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - "Been a one woman man for 44 years & a one Bank man for 54. Never found a better bank, never needed a better woman" (NBTC) n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - Being Good With Numbers Isn't The Only Reason You Can Count On Us (NBTC) n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - A Blue Ribbon Bank You Can Believe In (JNB) n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - Deposit Account Rules (JNB) 1985 Jul 1, Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - Fun Time Loans--Financial Peace of Mind (JNB) n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - "I've got a problem most of you wish you had. I've got more money than I know what to do with" (NBTC) n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - Introducing... The New Mark of Progressive Banking In Central Virginia (NBTC) n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - Introducing Ready Reserve For Everyone Who Had Strong Feelings About Having Their Personal Checks Bounced (NBTC) n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - It Makes Sense To Get A Vacation Loan From National Bank Even If You Think That's A Lot of Nonsense (NBTC) n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - "I worked hard for 42 years to earn Social Security checks. Thank Goodness I don't have to move a muscle to get them into the bank" (NBTC) n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - Look For Us--Totally Satisfying Banking (JNB) n.d., Advertising posters (2 copies) (Oversize 12)
  - National Bank's Paying 4 1/2% on Passbook Savings Account (NB) n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - NO--No limit to the number of checks you can write (NB) n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - On Dec 31, 1979, These 5 Virginia Banks Pooled Their Resources To Form Jefferson Bankshares, Inc. n.d., Advertising posters (2 copies with color & one without color) (Oversize 12)
  - The Professional Banker Advertising Campaign, featuring: --Arbogast, W. Dale --Bell, William E. --Berry, James R. --Dabney, Hovey S. --Daniel, Channing W. --Maxwell III, Richard D. --Morris, Edwin H. --Morris, James R. --Morton, Philip M. --Philips, Frederick H. --Stacy, Burton E. 1970 Apr 8, Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - Put A Little Freedom In Your Pocket (JNB) n.d., Advertising posters (4 prints) (Oversize 12)
  - A Respected Name In Banking (JNB) n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - A Simple Comparison Between National Bank & A Savings & Loan n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - Soar With The Eagle To 50-Plus Banking (JNB) n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - A Statement From National Bank About Savings n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - Take 5% From National--A Savings Certificate Advertisement (NBTC) n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - The 10 Minutes You Spend With Us Can Be Worth Up To $10,000 To You (JNB) n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - There's Nobody Else--Savings and Investement Certificates (NBTC) n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - Why Our Interest Checking Is Bound To Be The Best In 25 Words Or Less (NB) n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
  - You Can Count On Us To Increase Savings To 5 1/4% n.d., Advertising posters (Oversize 12)
- Oversize Scrapbooks 1950-1978 (Oversize 13-15)
  - Richmond Times-Dispatch& The Richmond News-Leader--Scrapbook Containing News Releases, News Clippings & Photographs of National Bank 1958-1971 (Oversize 13)
  - Scrapbook Containing News Releases, News Clippings & Photographs of National Bank and Trust Company 1971-1977 (Oversize 14)
  - Richmond Times-Dispatch& The Richmond News-Leader--Scrapbook Containing News Clippings & Photographs of Southern Bank 1950-1976 (Oversize 15)
  - Richmond Times-Dispatch& The Richmond News-Leader--Scrapbook Containing News Clippings & Photographs of The Bank of Goochland, The Bank of Powhatan & Southern Bankshares, Inc. 1976-1978 (Oversize 15)
- Architectural Drawings & Maps 1971-1989, n.d. (Oversize 16)
  - Architectural drawing for site plan, National Bank & Trust Company, Charlottesville, "Blue Ridge Office" ȣ7133 1971 Aug 27 (Oversize 16)
  - Architectural drawing for elevations for National Bank & Trust Company, "Blue Ridge Office & Computer Building," Route 29, Rio Road #7155 A4 1972 May 1, 2 sheets (Oversize 16)
  - Architectual drawings for site plan, Germanna Drive-In Office, National Bank & Trust Company, State Fram Blvd., Albemarle County #7212 PP-1 1972 Jun 20, 6 sheets (Oversize 16)
  - Architectural drawing for site plan, new office National Bank & Trust Company, State Farm Blvd., Albemarle County #7910 PP-1 1979-1980 (Oversize 16)
  - Architectural drawing for Stuart's Draft new office for the Jefferson Bank of the Valley #7914 SP-1 1980 Apr 9 (Oversize 16)
  - Architectural drawings for Jefferson National Bank, Winchester, Virginia 1985 (Oversize 16)
  - Blueprint Map of the Commonwealth of Virginia, Department of Transportation, Office of Public Affairs, County Seats & Independent Cities 1989 Jan, 3 copies (Oversize 16)
  - Official State Map, Department of Transportation n.d., 3 copies (Oversize 16)
  - Map #9439 [Virginia] by the American Map Corporation n.d. (Oversize 16)
  - Map #444 Counties & Towns of Virginia 1971 Aug 27, 2 copies (Oversize 16)
- Audiovisual & Miscellaneous Material 1949-1997, n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
  - Video Cassette Tape Recordings 1986-1995, n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "Shenandoah," "Shopping" 1986 Dec 22 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "Safe Bank" 1989 Apr 3 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "Safety" 1989 Apr 19 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "Yes! Loans" 1991 Aug 22, 2 tapes (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - PBS Documentary "Mountain Steam: The Alleghany Central Railroad" 1991 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "Motion Path" (Revision) 1992 Mar 31 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "Motion Control" 1992 Apr 6-7, 2 tapes (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "Blue Spot" 1992 Apr 9 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "Blue Spot," "Business Banking" (no voice), "Business Banking" (with voice) 1992 Apr 13 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "Blue Spot" 1992 Apr 15 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "Blue Spot," "Busness Banking," "Problem?" 1992 Apr 16 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Educational & Training Communications "The Governor's Report" (Anti-Crime Partnership) 1992 Apr (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Longworth Communications, Inc., "The Governor's Report," "Rural Virginia" 1992 Aug (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Commonwealth Center For Education of Teachers "Invitational Team Case Competition" 1992 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "Motion Control" 1993 Mar 22 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "Spring" 1993 Mar 23 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "TJ/Loans," "Auto Loans," "Home Loans" 1993 Apr 6 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - WCVE/VHTJ Copyright "For The Record" 1995 Oct 11 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "We're Not Stuffy," "Cleaning Lady," "Shenandoah," "Shopping," "We Believe--Sunrise," "We Believe--Truck," "Wonderful Person," "I'm Good," "Safest Bank" n.d. (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "New Hires" n.d. (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "Cross Sell Manager" n.d. (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "We Believe--Sunrise," "We Believe--Truck," "Wonderful Person," "I'm Good" n.d. (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "Underwriting Spots" ("Columbus," "Welk") n.d. (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - National bank and Trust Co. TV Commercials Produced At WHSV-TV n.d. (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - National Bank (Advertisement Spots) n.d. (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank Untitled n.y. Oct 16 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank Untitled n.d. (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
  - Audio Cassette Tape Recording 1971-1997, n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - VBA Convention--Speech Given By Mr. Jim Hayes "What's My Job" (Homestead) 1971 Jun (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Bank Administration Institute "Cash Dispensing and Automatic Teller Machines" 1973, 2 tapes (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - University of Virginia--Graduate School Business Administration Marketing [Resources?] 1974 Feb (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - United Virginia Bank--Correspondent Bank Seminar 1974 Nov (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Dabney-Golembe Interview 1977 Jan 15 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Annual Report Discussion 1978 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - National Bank and Trust--University of Virginia Basketball 1978 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - National Bank--The After-Christmas Christmas Club (WPED) 1980 Oct 22 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - National Bank and Trust Company--The After-Christmas Christmas Club "Spots 771, 772, 773, 774" 1981 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - JDK Music Production "Jefferson Bank Music Demo" 1992 Apr 1 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank Radio Spot 1994 Aug 15 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "CD/Satisfied" (Radio Spot) 1995 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank Untitled 1996 Jul 8 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National bank Loan Spot "Green Eggs & Ham" (Final Version) 1997 Apr 9 (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - American Bankers Association "Governing Council Winter Meeting" n.d. (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Untitled n.d. (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National from WVNZ n.d. (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank Randy Sparks "Oh Yes, I'm A Wonderful Person!" n.d., 2 tapes (Othertype Range 177 Shelf D)
  - Reel-to-Reel Tapes 1970-1980, n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank and Trust Company "National Bank Conversations" 1970 Mar 24 (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank and Trust Company Jingles "Closer To You," "Staying Alive," "Car Financing," "Our Banks," "Savings," "Independent," "Safety Deposit," "Legal Receipts" 1971 Jan (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank and Trust Company "Fisherville Bank Opening" 1971 Mar 11 (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank and Trust Company "Contemporary Jingle" 1971 Sep 13, 2 identical tracks (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank and Trust Company Complete "Closer To You" Jingle Series 1971 Oct 19 (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank and Trust Company "New Hours" (WUVA) 1972 Sep 10-16 (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - 1978 Annual Report Management and Director Discussion 1978 Dec 19 (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - Two Recordings of MMN and MSI Presentation To JBI Employees Officers and Advertising Directors 1980 Jan 28-30 (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank and Trust Company "Donut," "Tag" n.d., 2 copies (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank Advertisement Spots n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank and Trust NB-139 Letter Response including "Hours" and "Pens" n.d., 3 copies (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank and Trust Company "National Bank G'ville Interviews WJMA" n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank and Trust Company Six 60-Second Spots including "Bank Americard/Mastercharge," "Trust Department," "Installment Auto Loan," "Savings," "Institutional," "Checking" n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank and Trust Company Two 60-Second Spots "People First," "Savings" n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - Pepper & Tanner Bank Series "Institutional," "Savings," "Loans," "Institutional with Pad," "Checking," "Christmas," "Full Service," "Drive-In," "Credit Cards," "Acappella" n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank "Professional Banker" n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank and Trust WELK Spots including "Vacation Loan--Samantha & Simon," "Pal Loans," "Time & Temp" n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - Christmas Music n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank and Trust Four Identical Contemporary Jingles (New Mix) n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - Two Empty Reel-to-Reel n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank "Interest Checking" n.d., Missing Reel-to-Reel (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
  - 16mm Motion Picture 1949-1973, n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - The National Bank of Orange Banking Film "Pay To The Order Of" 1949 Sep 20 (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank and Trust Company 30-Second Spot "New House" 1973 Mar (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank and Trust Company 30-Second Spot "Boat"--Savings 1973 Apr (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank and Trust Company 60-Second Spot for "Boat"--Savings 1973 Apr (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank and Trust Company 30-Second Spot for New Logo "Skiff" n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank and Trust Company 30-Second Spot "Boat" n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank and Trust Company 60-Second Spot for New Logo "Skiff" n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - National Bank and Trust Company 60-Second Spot "New House" n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - Colony Productions for National Bank 30-Second Spot "Skiff" n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - Colony Productions Projection Prints For National Bank and Trust Company "New House," "Skiff" n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
  - 1" Videotape 1985-1993 (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "Cleaning Lady" 1985 May 23 (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "Shopping," "Shenandoah" 1986 Sep 4 (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "We Believe--Sunrise," "We Believe--Truck" 1987 Nov 10 (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "Business Banking" 1992 May (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "Blue Spot" 1992 Apr 15 (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "Busness Banking" 1992 Apr 15 (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank "Auto Loans," "Home Loans" 1993 Apr 5 (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
  - Miscellaneous Material including Phonograph Recording, Computer Tape and Jaz Disk 1988-1997, n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank Randy Sparks "Oh Yes, I'm a Wonderful Person" 1988 (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - Jefferson National Bank Official Admark Transfer Copy 1997 (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - Application Data Research--Record Count n.d. (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)
    - Computer disk with file "Business Access Brochure" ca. 1996-1997 (Othertype Range 117 Shelf D)